So, obviously I stayed another week in
Maine. Uh, it's hard to get me out of
Maine. It's my, uh, happy place. Um,
so I've been doing this now for two
years. Um, I've been doing a weekly
podcast with Anthony Pompiano since
April of last year. Uh the weekly that I
do on the YouTube has been 90%
preparing people for how AI would
disrupt macro, how it would disrupt the
market, multiple compression, all kinds
of things with the ultimate um endgame
for me and endgame is an important word
because it's going to be highlighted in
here. Beware of the endgame bias.
uh the endgame which is that AI would
lead to a massive boom in
entrepreneurship. It would disrupt all
public companies and that disruption
would begin much sooner than people
realize really beginning when AI
adoption started which obviously
happened this year with AI agents. Uh on
an weekly we talk probably about 50%
about crypto when you average them all
together. when there's nothing going on
in Bitcoin, we don't talk as much about
it, but it's really uh more crypto.
This video is the most important one
that I've done because the ultimate
endgame for me was a point where Bitcoin
starts to show up in its third wave, in
its adoption phase, in the same way that
AI did a year ago. And I've said
repeatedly that I believe crypto will be
viewed by everyone on the investment
side a year from now in the same way
that the infrastructure trade is today.
The difference is Bitcoin does not get
disrupted by AI. It is the purest AI
trade. So if I am right and you guys
watch me for some reason, whether it's
to provoke thought, uh it's not for my
looks, it's not for my ability to speak,
it is because I must bring something to
the table that gives you guys something
to include in your own process. I'm not
here to tell you what's going to work. I
believe Bitcoin will go higher. I
believe crypto will go higher because as
Mark Andre said,
why Bitcoin matters. If you haven't read
the paper and you've been watching this
video, it is now time to make sure that
you watch it. You read it this weekend
and you go see why Mark Andre said that
the Bitcoin white paper was one of the
most important advancements
in the computer and where we would be 20
years from when he wrote that. And that
was 2014. We are now at 2026. I'm sick
and I have always been sick of listening
to people debate Bitcoin. It's going to
hear. is going to hear if I heard
another person doubt that it's going to
go higher. Our job is not to g to guess.
Our job is to try and put together a
framework that we believe and when the
tape starts to tell you that something
is important is going on, that's when
you want to start to pay attention. I
mentioned two weeks ago on Anony's uh
podcast and on mine that I believe that
the end of July would be looked back on
as the most important inflection point
for all of us making money. situational
awareness bottom with VS up at extreme
levels. The market structure has clearly
changed in the stock market.
Tokenization is coming and people are
going to have to look at the facts on
the equation. I'm going to go through a
lot on Bitcoin today, but a lot of it is
combining and it's number four that
matters for all of you. Bitcoin is a
hedge to the time risk that all of you
are going through. If you're an
economist trying to tell me about the
jobs market and the inflation data and
all of the garbage that is associated
with looking back and thinking that your
job is still relevant compared to where
it was five years ago, six years ago,
seven year, everything has changed. The
academic fed is no longer relevant.
Whether it's hawkish or dovish is no
longer relevant. It might be relevant
for a week, but it hasn't been relevant
for a long time. And this video is going
to try to take you through the journey
of all the noise that you listen to
every week and how if you're trying to
make money and you're coming in to watch
me from this point on until Bitcoin goes
back under the 200 day moving average.
That'll be the point that I bail out and
say, "Okay, I'm not talking about it
anymore." Until that day comes, start to
focus on the AI macro nexus that is
coming. Let's start
now.
All right.
So, I just want to make sure you guys
see this. This is the thumbnail. I
posted this on X.
For the last year, we have watched AI
speed up competition. I didn't care
about the impact that AI would
eventually have on getting us to Bitcoin
until AI adap AI adoption was happening
at the enterprise level which is clearly
happening because you can see it with
the fastest ARR growth for a company in
the history of the world which is
enthropic
and using AI agents and once that
happens and you speed up competition you
speed up the ability of taking any idea
and rebuilding it with no people that's
what AI agents allow you to do
innovation cycles compress in time.
Everything compresses in time. I said
last week, AI agents can can work. Even
with the pantry flirting and the eating
and the lunch and the travel and all
that, the best case scenario, 70 days is
equal to a year.
My gut from managing people for a long
time and dealing with all the waste and
the travel time and the drinking and all
the things that go on is that it's more
like 10 to one. So when people tell you
year-over-year this is growing this
much, it doesn't mean anything because
that's human time. What ends up
happening is terminal value starts to
decay. And that's what this is meant to
show. And that's what we've seen with
the software names. At some point when
the competition is speeding so fast, you
can't value a company three years out
anymore because the speed of change is
going so fast that it eventually
disrupts every single company. And that
does mean including physical companies.
silver companies, uh, oil companies, but
they're the last in line, not the first
in line. The first is Adobe. The first
is the companies you've seen it go on.
But eventually, the entrepreneurs get
big enough, they get the ecosystem grows
fast enough. That's what Stripe is all
about. They are the ecosystem of
entrepreneurs causing the destruction.
They're just too small right now, but
they're growing at exponential pace. And
within three years, they will have
disrupted all business's growth. And
that's what you have to remember. the
value of stocks on discounted cash flows
in the future. It's all about growth and
if we have no certainty of growth, how
do you hedge that time risk? How do you
hedge that growth? This thing is not
disrupted by it. That is why it is the
purest AI trade. So for the last time as
a as AI speeds up and we start to get
into the abundance world where deflation
is the game, we're seeing that we're
talking about anthropic being subject to
deflation competition. the fastest
growing company that has gone in a
parabolic move. We're now worried that
they are slowing.
This thing's breaking out today.
Remember that as you're going through
and thinking about things in your
portfolio, you don't have to agree with
me, but if you have a zero zero%
position in this, you are saying there
is 0% chance of this because everything
in your portfolio will be disrupted.
Which is why I'm doing these
conversation the videos. It's also why
I'm launching the crypto part of this
too, which will go on the subscriber
site. So,
I want to do this because I am getting
subscribers going, "What about this
name? Are you still in this name? Is
this name going higher?" Guys, I am not
a stock picker. I am a thematic
portfolio guy that writes spotlight
pieces to highlight to you for yourself
how they fit into the AI trade and then
for you to go. I hate the fact that I
have to put disclaimers on anything, but
the reason you have disclaimers is
because I'm here to give you guys
education, not investment advice. If
you're in a name and you haven't traded
out of it, I trade all the time. I'm not
going to come on here and say I've done
this or done this based on on everything
that I'm doing. I told you I reduced my
positions in uh cryp or in the AI trade
back in May and June and I moved the
money into silver and Bitcoin. Those are
my largest positions. Now, I still have
Marll. It's a decent sized position. I
moved into Eli Lily, which made new
all-time highs this week. I've told you
where I've been moving things. The
application side is where I'm more
interested, but I still have
infrastructure names, but these names
I'm sitting in, and I think a year from
now, they'll be up more than the S&P,
but I do not think they're going to be
five baggers, six baggers, seven
baggers. Do I think silver is going to
outperform all those? Yes. Do I think
Bitcoin's going to outperform it? Yes.
Do I think Ethereum is? Yes. Do I think
micro strategy is yes. My goal is to
educate you and empower you both to use
AI and to get ready for the crypto merge
which is coming. If you don't think
about it and if you don't know enough
about it, that's what I'm here for is to
teach you guys. If you want to know more
about crypto, if you're an RAIA, a
financial advisor, and you've ignored it
and your clients have asked for it, you
can't ignore it anymore. Next year will
be a huge year relative to the market.
And I will go through the reasons why,
but the adoption phase of crypto is
going to go through the same adoption
phase we've we've seen with the
infrastructure. The difference is
there's no more growth assets left. You
cannot believe a public company will be
worth anything in three years relative
to what it is today. They need to grow
and growth is being disrupted by
competition. Crypto is a tiny odd lot.
The total size of the crypto market is
around $3 trillion. The Russell 2000 is
around three trillion. This is going to
grow massively faster. And the size of
it is going to grow because it is the
guard rails for what's about to happen.
The endgame bias. The Fed will raise
rates. Long-term rates will set off a
collapse due to debt and deficit. Oil is
going to 200. Inflation is too high. AI
is a bubble. These are all the stories
that I hear every single week. It's just
pick your one. An economist said they're
going to raise three time. I can go
through this over and over again. These
are noise. These are endgame bias by
everyone. Everyone will tell you this
can't go on. I get emails after emails
saying this will end badly. Okay, I'm
just going to buy some stuff, but this
is going to end badly. It is going to
end badly. But in my bad, it's not
because of this. It's because of
deflationary competition which causes
abundance and changes the structure of
the market. So if you for any reason
listen to me every week and at least
think that my view has some backing
behind it based on the facts and the
data and the amount of reading and
things that I've done on the topics of
AI. I use it all day long. You're going
to get a Grotbot
uh uh example today uh on how AI agents
have now been democratized. So, if you
can get that from an economist who's 59,
if you can get that from an investment
uh strategist who's 59, great. But the
only way you can talk about these things
is to have some historical domain
experience. And if you have domain
experience and you don't use AI, how can
you possibly listen to anyone who does
this? These were all wrong. They've all
been wrong. Could they be right
eventually? I I guess. But in the
meantime, you're losing money. So, I
think it's very important to stop with
the endgame bias. People know what the
endgame is. They say the same thing all
the time. And the same people said oil
is going to 200 or the same people
saying inflation's too high. They're the
same people say the Fed will raise
rates. It's all the same story. And I
know that because I have X to go prove
it. That's all they do. And they write
and they get paid for it. I'm not paid
to be bullish. I'm actually the most
bearish person I know on public
equities. It's just not today. It's in
the future. And maybe it never happens.
I'll change my views based on the basian
framework that goes on. Here's tenure
rates. I lived in Brazil for a long
time.
The currency was pegged the entire time
I was there until they had to move the
currency with the devaluation and then
Morgan Stanley brought me back to take
over the S&P book. This is a pegged
currency. This is tenure rates in the
US. How many people are giving you that
this is going to blow off to the upside?
Have you seen the chart? This is a a
wedge. This is just it. Yeah, that's all
great except you're fighting the
government. They don't want it to go
higher. So, is it really the best bet to
sit there and say they're going to let
this go to 9 10%. Or is it a better bet
to say we've watched this game before,
they'll just keep doing this, but
because Japan is having to do something
in terms of raising rates, but their
rates are lower than ours in terms of
short rates. So, the yen and the BOJ
situation is September will be a big
event. The question is, was the yen
signal what I thought it was? And as of
right now, it absolutely was because the
Treasury announces increased sizes of
nominal end liquidity support, the most
important news of the week, and helped
get Bitcoin moving.
Then, of course, he couldn't stop there.
Oh, could be more than four billion.
We've seen this before. This is the old
bazooka trick. This is the old I want to
stop the market from targeting this
there. They believe, as he said on CNBC,
these are mispriced. This is not the
right price for yields.
He's going against GDP that's going
higher. He's going against inflation
that's higher than what the Fed has
said. All of these things are true. You
got PMIs in terms of the Philly Fed and
the Empire new orders, which are
basically at the same level that equates
to a 60 PMI, which I've talked about for
a year. the growth is good,
but they're saying they don't want
yields to go higher because we have a
debt and deficit problem. And so history
suggests not to dismiss Bessant's move
on the yen. Basically going against
intervention is a very very dangerous
game particularly when it's coordinated
against other countries. He's doing
unconventional moves to try and help.
He's leaning on the Fed to help with
FEMA. Again, when you see multiple
stories going on, you have to be
careful. Besson is seen as a political
actor. He's focused on midterm. This is
all noise, guys. This is just stuff
going on. The academic Fed versus the
inflation target of the future. I wrote
this on a August 18th of 2025, almost a
year ago to the day. And within there,
this is before Worsh was chosen. I
talked about how Scott Besson was
interviewed on the AllIn podcast
following the AI action plan. If you
haven't listened to it, go listen to it
again because remember Scott Bessant was
heavily involved with choosing Kevin
Worsh. They went through this and if
this administration is one thing, if
they bring someone in, they are going
through a vetting process to figure out
if they're going to agree with the way
they view the world, which is very
different than the way academics view
the world. Besson in a recent interview
with Nikkei. So this is he stressed that
the Fed's role is now expanding far
beyond traditional interest rate
management and because of this the next
Fed chair must be someone capable of
thoroughly examining the institution
itself not just inheriting old
frameworks. Are the economists that
you're paying to listen to still using
old frameworks that they were taught in
college
because this administration wants them
to examine it and change them. uh task
forces. Besson argued the Fed's
leadership should be proactive and
forward-looking, able to anticipate how
structural changes such as AIdriven
productivity, fiscal dynamics, meaning
the debt and deficit situation and
geopolitical pressures
[sighs]
will reshape the economy. The next Fed
share in short must be an adaptive
leader prepared to rethink the Fed's
mission in light of the rapid innovation
and fiscal realities. That's it in a
nutshell. AI needs to raise money. It
needs the back end of the curve for the
next year to two years until the free
cash flow for the people borrowing money
gets to a level where they can just use
free cash flow from their ROIC, assuming
again they get there. Regardless, they
don't want rates going higher and they
understand this is happening because for
the first time in a long time, we have a
lot of supply coming to the market.
Broadcom's coming to the market with a
massive deal. So,
as you read this and go through it and
pause it here, you will see that what
you're witnessing and what's going on
with Kevin Worsh, who is connected to
Scott Bessant. The belief that people
have was that there'd be no Fed
independence. But somehow or another,
people actually believe what Scott
Besson wants is lower rates, but Worsh
is just going to do whatever he wants.
So, we questions Fed independence, but
on the same side, people are willing to
say, "Well, no, no, no. He's going to
raise rates." Even though I I I just I
I'm a handicapper. That just doesn't
seem like knowing this administration
something that is going to be real. So,
you can sit there and say that, but if
the people that are saying that we're
saying three rate hikes and they refuse
to give up on the three rate hikes, even
though we've had softer inflation data,
we've had softer labor data, and we've
had the yen signal. How are you being
honest as a handicapper? There's new
news that came in over the last two
months and you haven't adjusted your
view from three rate hikes. That is the
main problem with listening to anyone
right now on the Fed who's sitting there
still saying rate hikes. Are they saying
it because they believe it or are saying
they because it want it? Are they saying
because Iran is still going on and oil
I'll show you the oil thing in a little
while. Listen to the interview and just
go through it. Then on July 6th, I wrote
the art of unlearning the Fed. And this
again, the inspiration came from that
same podcast. Besson's belief that
AIdriven productivity shifts demand. A
forward-looking Fed has real merit. AI
is progressing at an unprecedented pace.
And in a world defined by exponential
innovation, relying on backward-looking
models is too slow.
If you believe, as I do, that the
deflationary pressures from AI are about
to accelerate and you believe that you
should be, I don't know, shrinking the
amount of meetings,
you're actually trying to slow down
time, you're trying to make sure that
you're not moving too fast at this pace,
going and doing everything he's doing,
the task forces, the data, finding new
data, finding new ways to look at
inflation, whether or not it's the right
thing to do, It's definitely something
that has to be done and he's doing it.
So all these task forces are to adjust
monetary policy the way it's been done.
So using the old playbook is not there
to build data centers and the rest would
affect demand demand and could increase
demand by a few tents. This is Kevin
Worsh speaking at his press conference
on the supply side of the economy to
increase the potential output of the
economy that could be considerably
bigger. So his point on this is that
short term the capital spending story
might inflate inflation a little bit but
the deflationary pressures that will
come from the supply side of the economy
changing in the future are far bigger if
that's what he believes and he said in
front of Congress at his testimony why
should you doubt him at this point now
he doesn't make the final decision on
rates but we all know at this point
unless there's an egregious way meaning
unless the inflation data is surprising
on the high side. At the end of the day,
there's no way I can see him raising
rates unless he's outvoted. I just don't
see how it's going to happen. And again,
I think it's a bad bet with the data
that we've seen. So again, I'm going to
go back to how important that week was.
The yen signal. Go read the paper if you
haven't read it yet. It's the
summertime. I know people have been kind
of going through the motions. It was a
brutal July for a lot of people in the
AI trade. August so far has been a very
good month despite what the noise you're
hearing. Almost everything is up 3% um
for the month. We have a little back and
forth. We go all over the place, but
it's there. Um this is the part that I
put in. Over the next 12 months, I
expect agents to move rapidly from tools
that assist humans to systems that
increasingly act on their behalf. I'll
show Grockbot today. That means more
productivity, but it also means more
pressure on employment, wages, tax
receipts, and the political response
required to manage the transition. The
economic system will simultaneously be
asked to finance unprecedented
investment in comput infrastructure
while adapting to a technology capable
of reducing the need for human labor
across an expanding number of
industries. That is a fact. That's not a
guess. All of that is true. All of it.
We're seeing it. It's just a fact. The
economic system is being changed because
of AI agents and they're accelerating at
an an insane pace right now seen through
the ARR. This only started in January.
We haven't really started the usage. We
are in the bring it on, show me how we
can do it side. That is just starting.
And that is the reason why crypto is
starting to become more important
because as I go through here, the end
intervention was not the crisis. Gold is
not yet singling a crisis. AI agents
have not yet transformed the economy.
But the pressure from all three is
beginning to show up at the same time.
That is the nexus point. And I believe
we will look back on the last week of
July as one of the moments when the
merging of the creditbacked fiat world
and the AI fueled digital economy
stopped being theoretical and began
began showing up in markets. That
collision course between the
creditbacked fiat system and the crypto
world is what's happening now. Besson's
being called the most interventionist
treasury chief in decades.
Trump at the crypto event still with his
guy there said Fed interest rate policy
he's bemoning it says US should be
paying much less if you listen to it he
thinks our rates should be down he's
publicly saying that is he applying
pressure to Bessant or to Worsh no he's
doing a great job
but he also renewed his attacks on the
Federal Reserve so he might be saying
things about Worsh but don't think this
isn't his goal is to make sure there's
no rate hikes
So, let's go back. Bitcoin Segue, a
peer-to-peer electronic cash system. We
propose a solution to the double
spending problem using peer-to-peer
network. If you haven't read the Bitcoin
white paper, now that I've said to you
why Bitcoin matters by Mark Andre in
January of 2014, must read for alpha in
the future. Now, you've got the Bitcoin
white paper on your homework. In
Bitcoin, you cannot spend the same
monetary unit twice. The fiscal system,
you can spend today's income and
simultaneously borrow against tomorrow's
income. Old system completely breaking
down. New system being born. Satoshi
built Bitcoin to eliminate double
spending of money. This was the white
paper. This was the solution. The
sovereign debt system permits something
Bitcoin does not. The repeated spending
of future time. There's the time thing
again.
It's all going to change from this point
going forward.
This is why when you go through the AI
macro nexus, you know, sheet and for
those of you who got it last week on the
RAIA side and have signed up for me to
do presentations, the next constraint is
financial crypto rails for AI agents.
This learning curve will be massive
compared to these. So, you better be
ready and you better be on top of the
fact because when your clients ask you,
"Hey, what should we be doing in
crypto?" And you say, "We don't do it.
We don't have an answer. Let me get
someone on the phone who's credible in
the space and a guy with a hoodie shows
up." Or you're lucky enough to find
someone in the crypto space who can talk
about their vertical. The problem is,
how do you connect it back to what's
happening in the world and get a story
or a narrative that people can embrace?
Who are your clients? You're going to
have to find that
And that's the reason why I was doing
this because I know this is coming at
the White House this week.
This event went on. So the same week
that Scott Bessant is doing all of these
interventions in the last two weeks, the
quarterly refunding change in the
language, the yen intervention, the
buyback situation, publicly saying he
wants rates to be lower.
President Trump had all of the crypto
gangs there to basically say to the
Democrats.
If you don't sign the Clarity Act, we're
going forward anyway because this is
important to America. You can have it on
your voting block if you don't want to
have it. We're going forward. Both
applying pressure, but also saying it
doesn't really matter. This is like AI,
guys.
So the clarity act's been keeping a ball
below the water and this week it just
blew out of the water partly because of
the change from Bessant and partly
because of what's happening at the White
House. So there are catalysts that
happen that everyone was looking for.
Now Trump argued that crypto stable
coins prediction markets and blockchain
based finance tools are for maintaining
US financial dominance, keeping
innovation on shore and extending the
dollar's global role. Critical thing to
say, very important. They view this and
this is part of it. This is not let me
go buy Bitcoin because I want to
speculate on I want to make money. This
is the belief that just like AI having
the dollarbased system which the US has
had creates strength for them, they
can't allow China to have all of the
crypto side or it be outside the US. So
he connected crypto policy to AI
competition,
shifted to macro policy, saying interest
rates should fall when the economy is
strong. And then you can go through
these things from Brian Armstrong, from
Vlad, from Robin Hood, and from chain
link. All of this stuff is about the
global framework going on. So with all
that said, the one thing I've said, and
the reason I've been quiet on Bitcoin,
if you notice my demeanor change, it's
because of this. as Jesse Livermore
taught us all in reminiscence of a stock
operator. For those of you who are new
to investing and you want a good book to
read, this is a great book, especially
if you're a trader. If you haven't read
it, um I highly I highly recommend
reading it. The tape does not concern
itself with the why and wherefor. Don't
argue with the tape. The object of
reading the tape is to ascertain how and
when to trade. This one here and all of
them, I don't want to fight the tape.
So, when we're in a bare market, meaning
we're below the 200 day moving average,
I can buy some stuff. I can go through
it, but I'm not going to talk to it to
you guys about it other than just say, I
still believe it's going to bottom here
and it's going to go higher, but it may
go down before it goes up. But once it
gets above the 200 day moving average,
then I get more interested. Great
traders do not force the market to fit
the story. They let the tape update the
story. That's why all of the things that
I said had been going on for a while.
And like I showed two weeks ago from
HOL,
all of these bad events were going on
and Bitcoin was still trading well while
the tech bubble was unwinding.
I thought Bitcoin was a tech
beta trade. So somehow or another,
Bitcoin was hanging in there when bad
news was there.
And so here's what we get. That looks
like trying to hold a ball underwater.
And eventually the pressure came out.
Three massive candles in a row breaking
the 200 day moving average in Bitcoin.
Ethereum, same thing. You can't see it
here, but also the 200 day moving
average just turned up in Ethereum.
Very powerful signal.
I've talked to you that I believe
Ethereum should outperform. I have a
good amount of Ethereum. I didn't have
any Ethereum until really recently. Um,
and the reason is because I believe that
this is going to be based on the
ecosystem. I believe Beta is going to
lead in crypto and Bitcoin will not be
the leader. If I'm right about what's
happening, the other name should lead
and Ethereum should lead because this is
about the ecosystem being invested in.
And I'll talk more about that.
If you read my ex post, you saw this
chart.
Sigma moves. Guys, first of all, for
those of you who reach out and say you
show a lot of charts where you don't
explain what's going on, I will explain
this one. So, in the way to look at
things in both price and time, if Micron
right now has a uh a 20% rise, meaning
it goes from 900 to,00 you don't think
twice about it because it's been doing
that regularly. It trades at 100
volatility which means a normal daily
move in that thing is 6%. So if it's 6%
you get a 20% move. Okay, view it is
this way. That would be a three standard
deviation move on a daily basis. What
this is is this is the weekly moves. So
for a weekly move I'm taking the six-day
volatility of Bitcoin. Before we moved
this week, last Friday it was 23. So on
a daily basis 23 V is about 1 and a.5%.
The reason I can calculate that in my
head is because you take whatever that V
is, it's a daily annualized V. And if
you want to convert it into something
that you can do in percentage terms, you
take the square root of 252 trade days,
that's about 16. You divide the V 23 by
16, you get one and a half%. Now, if you
want to do weekly, you're taking that
same number, which is 23, and you're
dividing it by the square root
of 52 weeks. So, that's seven. So, let's
say 20, let's let's take it 23 vol
divided by 7. That's about 3% a week is
a one standard deviation move. We moved
by 22% this week. So, you get a seven
sigma move. So, that's how you normalize
things on movements to decide how big
and powerful of of a move it was based
on how it's been trading for the last 60
days. I chose 60 days because that is
two months worth of data. Um, and I say
two months because Bitcoin trades 60
seven days a week. Um, here were the
last two
highs, the only other two in the last
decade on a weekly basis that were
greater than five. One was April 7 7th,
2019,
January 15, 2023. You can see where the
V was. So, not too far off. This is the
way Bitcoin trades. It goes through a
bare market. All the sellers are gone.
And as we all know, for many of you who
just hold like me, I've never sold a
Bitcoin in my lifetime. You are left
with the fact that it eventually gets
quiet. The 60-day V eventually drops
down before the move. So this time it
was 23. In 19 it was 29. In 23 it was
27. This time it was 23. And then this
was the weekly move. So a very similar
time. Now let's go see if those points
were important.
Huh. Here was the one where it started.
Now this is a daily chart. That was the
week. We got these two big candles. And
guess what? We crossed above the 200 day
moving average. And we doubled very
quickly in the next two months in that.
That was back in the 19 one.
Oh, same exact thing. We break above the
200 day moving average back in 2022.
And this one a little bit more grumpy on
the way up, but still worked its way to
being up close to doubling very quickly.
And then took a little bit more time,
went through another phase. Um, the
point being on this for you guys,
the pattern's resuming and I hate to say
it as I said in the post, but it's like
the four-year cycle. I mentioned last
week that or the week after here that
the end signal was here. We got this
boost that was a multi-igma move in
gold. Very similar. It was a 7% move. I
showed it was one of the largest moves
in the last 15 years. It's continued
through and is back above the 200 day
moving average. So, we are getting some
sort of a debasement trade. We are
getting whatever you want to call it.
Silver was up big, too. I made a lot of
money on my silver stuff this week. Uh,
for those of you asking on the silver, I
am long SLV and I am long SIL. SIL is
much bigger. I like the miners because I
believe this stuff the miners are just
trading way too cheap relative to where
the metal is. Regardless of that, I got
both of them. So, let's go read one of
the posts I put in about this move in
Bitcoin. Sentiment is low. Jack Besson
is quoting Satoshi in Expose. The
Treasury Secretary is quoting Satoshi
and this is recent tech momentum V is at
45ear highs. I'm going to take you guys
through the fact that if you're running
a portfolio and you've got a 60-day
volume on one instrument which is 23 and
you have a 60-day V on something like
Micron which is 120. Um,
I don't think people have fully embraced
how important this is for Bitcoin.
People invest in beta.
This stuff is going to be stuck in the
mud. I will go through V, but I just
want to say this to you. V is like going
into the ICU at the hospital. When your
vitals are that severe and you end up in
the ICU, when you come out of the
hospital,
think of situational awareness day, that
tech momentum came out of the hospital,
you're not going to be back to normal
for a long time. It's going to take a
long time for this V to come down, if it
ever does. And as I've said, market
structure has changed. The reason this
stuff trades like that is because of the
terminal value destruction. You cannot
value companies three three years from
now. This is not just a Micron story.
I'll show you IBM later. You can go look
at Adobe. You can go All of these
companies are going through the same
thing on the on the uh on the option
side. You start hearing people talk
about dispersion and it continues to be
just all over the map in terms of all of
these names are moving at high volume,
but the index is not moving. That's
exactly what I would expect when S&P
earnings are going at 30, 40, 50%. And
the names are going all over the map.
That will continue because we are never
going back to a 8% earnings cycle and
GDP of three. That's never happening
again in an AI world. So adapt to the
new market structure and just realize
Bitcoin benefits because it's a growth
asset. And once it starts going and
people go, "This is beta." This
community is going to push this baby. So
get involved because it's coming. AI
agents are about to change global
economy measurements and the new Fed
chair has five task forces to
restructure the way monetary policy is
done, leaving academic economist lost
while the Treasury Secretary is doing
unconventional blah blah blah. As
Michael Sailor says, you don't find
Bitcoin, Bitcoin finds you. We are at
the Bitcoin finds you moment. If you're
trying to make money for investors and
you need to make more than what the S&P
can give when the S&P is giving you 20
25% a year, it's not going to help you
to go invest in stocks that are going up
25% a year. It's not going to help you
invest in stocks like Nvidia which go up
30% every year, but people hate the
stock because it doesn't go up 50 or 60
or it doesn't go up ever relative to the
S&P which I'll highlight as well, but it
still outperforms.
Going to be a good video this week.
Hopefully you guys are enjoying it so
far. We're still early in this. All
right, Satoshi,
America will lead or America won't. It's
not more complicated than that. I
believe Satoshi once said it best. If
you don't believe me or you don't get
it, I don't have time to try and
convince you. Sorry. The importance of
passing the Clarity Act.
I'm just telling you guys, read the
news. Do not have an endgame bias. If
people aren't talking about this, they
don't know it. They're not involved.
This is a Bitcoin presidency and all of
the people at every level are pro
Bitcoin. Kevin Walsh on Bitcoin. This is
from January.
It could tell the world that it could
tell the world that things need to be
fixed. Yes, the old system is broken.
Bitcoin does not make me nervous. The
underlying technology is that white
paper. Go read it. If you don't believe
me, go listen to Kevin. He's the Fed
chair. It's just software. It's just the
newest, coolest, coolest software that
will provide us the opportunity to do
things we have never done before. Okay,
Bitcoin. I think of Bitcoin as a lot of
things, but certainly with every passing
day, getting new life as an alternative
currency. Ask your economist if they
believe in Bitcoin. Ask them if they use
AI and then get rid of every one of them
that says no to both. They cannot help
you going forward. They can help you
five years ago. So, if you want to know
about what the Fed would have done five
years ago, be my guest and go deal with
it. Treasury seeks public comment on the
Genius Act, proposing rulemaking. Now,
the Genius Act is not the Clarity Act.
And remember that was passed a while
ago. This is August 17th. Again, during
this week,
I said to you guys back in June, I no
longer wanted to be involved with this
stuff. I wanted to be involved with this
layer, the hardest layer to invest in.
Where do we get the applications? This
is not a software thing. The models are
all under pressure now in terms of
everyone's worried about them.
Anthropics,
they're valued at very high levels. Do I
think Anthropic could be worth three
trillion? Sure,
it's already worth two trillion. What is
three trillion going to give you? That's
a 50% increase. We get stocks moving
50%. Bitcoin was up 23% this week
because it's an application.
It's part of the crypto ecosystem. And
yes, I know Bitcoin doesn't benefit on
this. But as I've shown before, Bitcoin
is basically the S&P 500 of the crypto
world and eventually of the entire
ecosystem of investing. It is the only
store of value in the digital economy.
End of story.
I'm glad that Stan has entered the
crypto world in a way that can be
publicized. Um, I've heard him talk
about Bitcoin. uh his statements on
Bitcoin back in like 2020 and 2021 I
thought were brilliant because he said,
"I don't understand it." But when I talk
to kids, they all want it. They all
believe in it. He knows that this is
important. He knows you don't have to
understand it, and you certainly don't
have to do what Jeremy Grantham did the
week of the lows is go on and say he
wants to piss all over it and it's
garbage. What an horrible the most
ironic bottom of all time. Stan
Duckville reveals 23 million of
hyperlquid market structures changing.
Market structures changing. This is my
favorite one.
Standiller's Dukane family office adds
Bitcoin mining exposure through Bit Deer
Riot Hut 8 and iron while exiting Intel
and Micron. That's the exact same trade
that I make. I I like it when stands on
uh on my playbook. I like it. the end
signal an AI max macro nexus point. Why
am I bringing this up again?
It's the merge time, guys. So, it brings
me to the next intersection, the AI Max
make macro nexus crypto. So, again,
think about what Stan is doing.
Regardless of his reasons on it, he's
looking at public companies and I'm sure
if he had the ability and maybe he does
of being involved in some of the tokens
and I'll go through some some of the
charts in terms of what the ecosystem is
doing. But if AI is creating a digital
economy increasingly populated by
autonomous agents, then that economy
will require digitally native money,
collateral, settlement, identity. At the
same time, if the response is the debt
burden of the existing fiat system
increasingly requires liquidity
creation and currency debasement, then
scarce digital assets become more
relevant, not less. These two forces are
approaching each other from opposite
directions. The old system is ending.
The new system is beginning. The new
system is accelerating and going to get
all of the investment in the next phase.
This is 101 of finding growth that is an
innovation that will be changing the
world. just because you don't understand
it. By investing in the old aging system
which cannot deal with AI agents, public
companies cannot deal with AI agents
regardless of what they tell you. An AI
native company can adapt quickly. A
public company, how long is it going to
take for them to install agents and use
them in a way? The only reason they can
benefit is because their revenues are so
big. So they will benefit until they
stop being able to cut expenses and grow
their revenues. At some point that will
happen in my opinion. So again, you
don't have to believe me, but you're
watching this for a reason. At least
incorporate it in there, and I'm trying
to educate you with the things to read.
So combine what happened with Stripe.
They purchased Open Router. So, Stripe,
as I've said multiple times and covered
um at least five or six times a year,
how important this company is to the new
financial guardrails, how they are the
ones that are moving quickly and doing
things. Combine what they did this week,
and I'm not going to read this, but you
guys can go read it. This is a letter to
investors explaining why they bought
Open Router. Why would they buy
something that is very important to what
companies are talking about? Meaning a
routing system where you can have open
source and you can have frontier models
and the router's deciding what the
cheapest one or the best one to use is.
Why would they do it? Well,
[clears throat]
that's not the only thing they're doing.
Stripes emerging AI agent economy stack.
So, if you want to look what the future
is going to look like, who should you be
paying attention to? these guys or JP
Morgan,
this is what they're buying. And they
can buy these little companies in in
their business and they're a big
company, hundreds of billions of dollars
in terms of valuation. But every single
part, I wrote a big paper on this when
they did this back two years ago. All of
these things go through and you can read
them on your own, but it's money,
compute, tokens, intelligent output,
revenue. They are basically creating a
stack for companies like mine, companies
that can use intelligence, tokens,
compute. They're saying money is being
transformed into these things and then
coming out the other side. You're
spending money on compute to create to
get AI tokens for the intelligence
involved with it. I do it all day long
in my business.
If you don't know enough about them,
this was an interview that came before
the open router announcement. This is
it's it's a great interview. It's on
A16Z podcast. I will put it in the
weekly podcast sheet with the transcript
or with the details and the link um for
the subscribers. Tokens are the new
dollar. Stripes will gay interviewed. Go
listen to it. Stripe has evolved from a
payments processor into a financial
infrastructure platform.
Isn't that to some degree what Amazon
became? what Google became what all
think about what's happening in front of
this except these guys are on the guard
rail side the financial side as I say to
my son who's getting a finance major but
is building agents every day you're an
entrepreneur dude you can build your own
business you don't have to go work for a
public company if you go work for a
public company you will be miserable the
same way I was day one at working at
Morgan Stanley I figured a way because I
was learning so much to keep that
suppressed I'm not born to work in a big
company. I don't like managing people.
I'll get into more of that when I show
you Grockbot. But my son is at this
stage where he has a finance degree.
Every company, whether it's a
construction company, a food company, a
uh a pension, it doesn't matter what it
is, you need to know finance for your
life, for everything. So, having a
finance degree is important, but
finance, which is where Stripe is
listed, they're building around that
need. I use Stripe.
Cost cutting is characterized as going
short your future potential. Building
more is going long. This is an
entrepreneurial mindset. This is an AI
native mindset. This is what they are.
They're not only talking about what
they're seeing. They're seeing explosion
in new company formation and faster
monetization. First half signups were
said to be up 50% year-over-year, while
newer startup cohorts are generating
substantially more rev than prior
cohorts. We are watching the
cannibalization of all revenue inside
the country by AI native businesses.
It's just that the number is small. The
Russell 2000 again is about three
trillion less than the size of Nvidia.
It will take time, but when you're
growing and you're seeing companies like
Anthropic go from a valuation of a
100red billion to two to three trillion
in less than 18 months, we've never seen
this before. This is what you're going
to see with other AI native businesses
and just wait till humanoids come. You
will see the same thing.
Agentic commerce is still missing basic
infrastructure. This is the reason why
we haven't seen the crypto side yet
because the Aentic commerce side is not
there yet. But once it comes, that's
where the growth comes in this. This is
where every hedge fund gets involved,
which will happen before the end of the
year because they will start to see the
numbers that's happening already and
value acrruel and all the revenues and
everything that's already going on and
realizing, oh my god, this thing is so
cheap. You're starting to see it with
companies like Figure. You're starting
to see it with the ones that I've
mentioned on here where people start
doing their homework and they're like,
"Wait a second. You're growing that
fast?" That's like AI growth.
It's connected to agents and it's going
to continue to grow rapidly, especially
while the government is giving the all
clear.
AI agents could finally make microp
payments economically important. Small
things. Stripe C stable coins
fundamentally a superior global payment
infrastructure. The central thesis
tokens are the new dollars. They see a
blurring between AI tokens and money. AI
macro nexus point.
If you don't know anything about crypto,
you're going to have a hard time in this
new world as tokenization comes. So,
here's the visual for you on this. The
cost per token continues to collapse.
The economic viable task rises. We're
getting Jeban's paradox. That's what it
looks like. That's why the pie is
getting bigger and bigger and going
there. That's why focusing on whether
Anthropic is going to have their
revenues grow or not is ridiculous.
They're never going to stop or they will
at some point, but not in the near term
because the pie is just growing too fast
because the adoption phase is still
here. We just don't have anybody still
going through in those size. It's better
than it was a year ago, but we're in the
early stages because nobody's using
agents yet, which I'll show you with
crackpot. So, this is the visual that
comes. AI breaks the relationship
between economic output and human time.
This is what I basically said, the old
economy, which economists like to do
research on, and the new economy, the
one that's built on capital, energy,
compute, tokens, human judgment, output.
So, if everyone's told you it's going to
blow up, the economy is not AI. It's all
AI, all this stuff. It's irrelevant. AI
is here. It's going to be here. The
capital will be raised. They will
continue to grow. If you got a chance to
read the paper I did last week, which is
all on the All-In podcast, go read it,
subscribers. If you were sitting at the
beach and you didn't get a chance, go
read it and just realize so you don't
have to call me about is Anthropic done?
Did you see the news? I don't care.
It's going higher. All of it. The
problem is the stocks are not going to
respond the way they did in the first
quarter which is frustrating people
because they're fully still at the
buffet table bloated with all of the AI
infrastructure stuff which is going to
outperform but I think people are
looking for 20 30 40 50% outperformance
and that's where I think it's going to
be an issue personally I think some of
them will but not all of them um don't
need to go through this again um it's
just really an emphasis that the
implications from an investment
standpoint is changing time which is why
Stripe is saying the singularity has
begun.
Don't forget tokenized stocks are
happening the other side of crypto and
this is the trading volume in tokenized
equities which again fits in a lot with
all the things that we were talking
about. So my 46 name equal weight
tokenized index over Bitcoin again
showing you that number one the
ecosystem is outperforming Bitcoin right
now which is good even outperformed this
week it's up for the year now the
ecosystem which includes Bitcoin but
it's equal weight so this is the 46 name
equal weight index uh of companies
Bitcoin's there and you can see how
highly correlated they are which again
is why if you want to invest in the 40
name equal weight. You can invest in
Bitcoin and you're going to get
basically the ecosystem. As this goes
higher, this will go higher. I don't
need to take you guys through now. If
you want to read some of my old stuff,
you can do that. If you want to call up
and call Mark Whailing, go ahead. I'll
give you guys why Bitcoin so important
to this group. So, these are the 10
verticals. Not going to read you all of
them. Two of them are up big this year.
The eight of them are down. the two that
are up. Digital monetary assets. This
this one, I'm not going to go through
the names in them, but there's a lot of
stuff going on in this AI agents in the
machine economy. Not surprisingly, doing
well. Um, these are all turned up this
week. They're highly correlated, but
there's 46 of them, including
up. We're destroying the valuation, and
that means multiples should compress.
That means as the S&P grows earnings 35%
as they look like they're doing this
year, maybe the S&P is up 20.
That's not the way it normally works. If
we were in a bubble, as people say with
everything going on and earnings growing
at unprecedented levels, no hiring, no
worry about the labor market, inflation
is in check despite what people tell you
uh on where it may go or may not go.
People still saying double-digit
inflation and stuff like that to scare
people. The reality is we should be up
50%, 100%. I saw the NDX or the NASDAQ
bubble. These names should be up a lot
more at this point. We we we had a
cancer vaccine this week for Christ's
sake with melanoma.
The market finished down for the week.
Like cancer vaccine,
this is not a bull market. Meaning this
is not a bubble.
You're going to have to hedge yourself
in the fact that this is already showing
signs of weakness. the aging fiat system
is showing up. And so again, the next
constraint is financial. It's not
physical. The physical side outperformed
the first part. That's what this year is
about. Next year, in my opinion, it's
all about understanding how to invest in
these. And most people haven't started
the work. They haven't done anything on
it. And I can tell you that based on the
questions I get now, a lot of the people
that watch this video and especially
this week given what happened with
Bitcoin
understand. But everyone else is trying
to trade treasuries and trade FX and
short the NASDAQ and wait for I I like
they're just wasting their time playing
around in an old age home with inside
that market. And now that the physical
part of AI has been discounted that
everyone's long it it's going to be
harder. That's the way markets go. And
then the stuff like Eli Liy, nobody
wants to hear me talk about Eli Liy.
Nobody. because they don't care about a
company growing revenues 50%
year-over-year unless it moves 100, 200,
300%. Bitcoin will do that. Ethereum
will do that. And that's where I think
people will go. Reach out to Mark
Whailing, get your sample package with
some of the work that we do. And for you
RAAS and FAS,
cancel your subscriptions at someone to
put me on there unless they have this.
If they have it, God bless you. You'll
get the work. But if you're paying
someone to talk about things that don't
matter, I don't know how that helps your
business going forward. And maybe it
helps it today and maybe you're in a
cushy job and you're just sitting there.
But I'm just telling you, we're living
in a world of so much noise and so many
questions are going to come from people.
You want to outperform and you got to be
on top of where the crypto side is.
Again, above the 200 day moving average
in Bitcoin. I am going to be pounding my
my my hands [snorts] on the table and
doing everything because the tape is
telling me to. I already had the story
and the narrative and believed in the
trend that was going on with the
government and the revenues and the
math. But now we have the tape as well.
Signal verse noise.
The endgame bias again. So again
this thing going to kill you. Okay. This
has been now one, two, three years of
tenure rates trading between four and
470 for almost the entire time. And yet
every technical person, every per they
want to tell you it's going to break
out. It's going to six. It's going to
seven. I've seen all the charts and
they're fighting the government. Can it
happen? Yeah. But when people start
telling me the United States of America
is an emerging market because we're
keeping rates, that is just BS.
Nvidia
again every time I hear a is a bubble
the reason it's noise is because until
Nvidia which is still growing their
earnings these are the numbers the last
three years this is insane
are they lower than they were here yeah
this was the beginning of the data
center buildout these are the
expectations here's the PE E based on
those numbers, a PEG ratio below one on
what should be trading probably double
where it is. I think the PE should be 50
based on what a bubble would look like.
So, just remember that that every time
you hear bubble, it's total BS. Oil,
first of all, going to 200 was a joke.
This is the year-over-year rate of
change in the sixth contract of oil,
guys. This is a fact. So when you tell
me that oil's up and we're going to 90
and we're going this, I don't care one
bit. I don't know how many cycles you
guys have lived through. Oil being up
27% year-over-year does not matter one
bit. Doesn't matter. So unless something
changes, and again, if it moved up here,
it doesn't matter. 40% year-over-year,
it doesn't matter. It doesn't matter
where it goes to. It matters if it sits
there at a long time. So, if you think
that that's going to happen, that's
great, but it's not there. So, go buy
oil stocks and just stop talking about
how it's going to take down the economy.
Here's the multiple in the S&P off next
year's earnings. This is the one. This
is the PEG ratio or sorry, the PE on
forward estimates on on the S&P. The
reason I want to bring this up is
because AI agents came out. Here's
what's happened to the PE of the S&P.
We've gone down 20%. So this is off next
year's earnings. That's how much
earnings have gone up despite the fact
that the price has gone higher.
This is not a bubble. If anything, this
is the market telling you we believe
terminal value is ending. We believe you
cannot value the market. I believe this
number will continue to decline in an
upward tape, meaning prices will
underperform earnings until we start to
see profit margins work out and then the
multiple will really collapse because
that means the entrepreneurship is
growing. I'm telling you this because
once the growth rate stops, this is
everyone's biggest position in the
world. And I am not positive on the S&P
500. I am not positive on this chart. I
believe this thing will continue to go
down because of AI.
Here's the performance of the S&P from
the end of 2022, that bare market to
now. The reason I want to show this is
because regardless of what my views are
in 2030, the reality is the S&P is
pumping out 20% a year despite all the
noise, despite the tariff fears, despite
uh SVB, despite uh the war in Iran. Like
guys, no matter what happens, you're
getting 20% in this. Like this has
become a thing. It's been a thing since
the great financial crisis. That's why
everyone calls it a bubble. But it just
continues. Could it fall at some point?
Yeah. But again, earnings are growing.
There's no there's no debt to be a
problem other than AI, and AI's revenues
are growing rapidly. Here's Nvidia. So,
if you've gone through all of the bubble
part, the deepseat fears, and all of the
things that have made you not belong in
Vidia,
it's up 109% since 2022.
Sorry, a year. It's up since 2022, 14.
You've had a 14 bagger despite all of
the AI bubble fears that have gone on.
And this is again 2022 is coming out of
the rate hike cycle, but it's also when
chatpt started. It's a 14 bagger. Micron
did a 14 bagger recently.
All right. This doesn't want to come up.
No. Having a little problem here with my
All right. Well, unfortunately, I knew
this was going to happen at some point.
Let's see if it's going to come up. All
right. I'm just going to leave this here
for now. So this is the Micro Strategy
uh returns
which are good. Uh they're up 600%
during that time period.
Let me see if I can switch this up
another way.
All right. Well, given the fact that I'm
not going to uh
restart the video.
I'm going to try and do this the
oldfashioned way. So, you guys are going
to bear with me. You're going to get
some enjoyment. There's going to be no
editing because this is a oneman show.
And now I see what the problem is.
Jord's got no Wi-Fi right now.
So, we're going to switch Wi-Fi because
you know me, I got a backup for that
stuff.
Love to give you more entertainment, but
unfortunately, this is the best I got,
guys. So, just bear with me here as I
get you back to where we were. Ignore
this part if you didn't fast forward to
it. I appreciate you sticking with me.
All right, see we're back. You just got
to give me time to get through things.
All right, MSDR
76% a year since 22. The reason I want
to bring this one up is 76% a year is
what it's produced since the end of
2022. And this is where the chart is.
What do you think's going to happen when
Bitcoin goes back to all-time highs? So
again, for all you noise people on Micro
Strategy, give me a break.
Uh, here's the month-to- date numbers
for the Globe.
Here are the year-to- date numbers for
the Globe. The Cosby, despite its crash,
just like that Micro Strategy thing, up
64%. Reason I'm bringing this up is for
all the noise you guys have heard on the
equity market and the bubble and
everything, the reality is it's just
fine. Signal verse noise.
Here's the JV thematic portfolio. So
again, I'm going to say this over and
over again. By the end of the year, I
expect new all-time highs in this. For
everyone who's just jumping in, think
we're going to do one of these again.
Not happening in my opinion. No chance,
no way, no how. I'll show you why. Do I
think we're going to grind our way
higher? Yes. Remember this fall the VA
exploded in the names. And like I said,
these names are coming out of the ICU.
They're just been released. That's what
this low was. They're not going to be
healthy again for at least 6 months.
Some of the names will, and the names
that I've highlighted to you, my biggest
positions with inside this portfolio,
um, Eli Liy doesn't really count. Silver
doesn't really count, but it's part of
the portfolio. Bitcoin doesn't really
count because you guys either don't
believe in it or it's not one of the
names in the thematic portfolio that you
guys um are in. Marll, I still love it.
I'm still sticking with it. I still
think there's a triple quadruple from
here in my opinion. Um take it for what
it is. It's just me thinking that it's
going to go higher over the course of
the next few years in a big way. I have
Microner
than it was before. Uh, and then I have
a lot of little names like Chamore,
Camores, um, Fluence, uh, a lot of
things in there that are just kind of
tiny positions that I still have that I
think eventually will, uh, be something
that I want to remember I have in there
and have a big bigger position in. Uh,
but they're very, very tiny at this
point. So, I think we're going to get
back and forth. I think these lows to me
are absolutely the low. I think we're
going to get through the highs. I just
don't think it's going to be in a
moonshot way like it was here. And most
importantly, some of the names like
Fluence is down 50% from where I think I
made my highest purchase in it. 50%. I
expect those types of things, guys. I'm
in the name. I'm in I have a little tiny
position in EOS as well, which is down
even more than that. So, just remember
the way that I deal with my portfolio is
going to be different than you guys.
trade your names based on the way you
trade risk. But right now, I think
crypto, Eli, Lily, silver, those are the
places that I rotated into and reduced
all those other things. The anthropic
thing, which scared the hell out of
people and got everyone going, it is
just complete noise, guys. For Christ's
sake, it's just complete noise.
Um, and Warren Pies put this out. I I
knew when I read it, it was going to
have an impact. I'm kind of surprised he
didn't realize. I didn't I like Warren a
lot but I mean we are seeing some early
cracks in our GPU availability data.
Anything that comes out like that people
are going to overreact to. So he's not
going to overreact but everyone else did
but have to call balls and strikes. We
are going to get to a point where GPU
pricing stops going higher. That does
not mean anything bad is going on guys.
Sorry. They shouldn't be going higher in
the first place. That was the whole
argument is that they depreciate at some
point. They'll just go sideways at a
high level. The fireworks show is over.
So, I just wanted to remind you guys
this as thinking about the way this is
going to move. I talked about it now
enough, but just keep this in the back
of your mind that one of the hardest
things for investors to recognize during
an exponential technical technological
transition is the difference between new
information and delayed understanding.
A lot's changed. A lot has changed.
Everyone's involved. So, this is where I
think we are in AI. The fireworks show
is over and the last couple weeks have
been the climax of an incredible
display. This is from the first week of
June. Maybe this is my time to be caught
going against the exponential tide.
Nope, it wasn't. It was exactly the
right time to be writing this paper
because June 6 was a time that if you
reduced your positions, you'd be in a
lot better shape and be a lot more
aggressive and not caring as much about
the back and forth. But I think the
warning signs are clear. More people are
now fighting against the bottleneck and
shortage side. This was my argument
against what would be the likely cause
against the agentic AI buildout itself.
For me, that usually means the all you
can eat AI buffet has left everyone full
and in need of a digestion period. I
still think that's going on. Um, I just
want to let you This is the Goldman
Sachs most crowded hedge fund names
overlaid with my thematic portfolio.
This just means that everyone's in the
AI infrastructure trade. Doesn't mean
it's wrong. Hedge funds do very well and
I'm sure that's going to work out well,
but they're in it, which makes it
harder. Secondly, this V differential,
you have to remember we had a period
where because it was going up so fast, V
was going higher while you were making
money. That is not a normal thing.
Normally, V is going higher and people
are losing money unless they're short
the market. The fact he made money while
the market was going higher. When Vin
kept going higher around here and the
market went down, that's when the issue
came in. This is overlaid with six-month
Vault. This is a structural difference
in the marketplace. And this is Micron
and IBM 90-day V overlaid with the S&P
90-day V going back to 2009 since the
great financial crisis. This has never
happened before, ever that you could
have the biggest companies in the market
having V spike and the S&P not move.
Tech momentum
5% moves a day in the Morgan Stanley
tech momentum. I just did a histogram of
it. uh none in this period post the
great financial crisis. Um 57 so far
this year. We're not even eight months
or through the year. We're not even
we're we're just at a point right now,
guys, when you go through this that it's
insane how much we've moved. Here's the
Nvidia pain trade. So here's their
earnings never stopping. So they just
keep going. They just the energ the
Energizer Bunny keeps going. This arrow
here points to the problem. Beginning in
2024 after Wow, this looks a lot like
the AI thematic trade. Let's assume
maybe this is where it was.
Okay, so
this is the price movement. Okay, this
is what happened to the PE ratio. So the
PE ratio peaked there
in the 40-50
area and now it's down at 19. That is
called moving higher in mud. That's the
Nvidia mud trap. You want to see how
painful it is from an alpha perspective
since June 7th of 2024. For the last 26
months,
this is Nvidia relative to the S&P.
Aside from these two bars, you've
basically been in the same death trap as
tenure rates.
So, if you're looking for this for
alpha, which is why everyone has boycott
it, which everyone complains about it,
here is how you made money. This is when
it outperformed from April of 25
to August of 25 for four months out of
26. That's the only time you made money
on the alpha side other than just
trading it. So this is what I expect for
most of the infrastructure trades. They
are going to be beast now because it's
discounted because we're going to see
multiple compression. Even though the
multiples are low, the PEG ratio on
Nvidia is no different than those PEG
ratios and it's been there almost the
entire time.
S&P 500 17% a year since 2024. Nvidia
was 30%. So you get that alpha
outperformance, but again it's very
frustrating to have it in there. So I
expect that to happen. All right, let's
move and start to finish this up. It's
gone too long, but it's an important
one. I'm going to blast through
Grockbot.
I would estimate my personal AI usage is
up like a hundred times. Completely
agree with Gavin Baker. That's why I put
this began managing people in my 20s
after 48 hours using Rockbot. One thing
is clear. Access to a team of 247 365
digital employees has just been
democratized from a usability
standpoint, not a price standpoint. This
thing still costs $200 a month. I
believe it's the cheapest you can get it
for. However, I would try it for a month
and I'm going to show you why. But
this has been unbelievable in a short
amount of time. So, for those of you who
have not gone through the open claw or
maybe you started it and you gave up or
Hermes or you used it and you got
frustrated because XYZ happened, this is
Elon Musk and Cursor's
solution and it is awesome.
So, I'm just showing you what it looks
like and just showing you how I started
it. It took me zero time to start. You
start, you have a chief of staff and
then you just start creating bots. You
just create them and you give them a
title, a writer, a gent commerce
research person.
Then the next stage for me is I went,
you know what, I want there to be a
chief of staff that reports to me and
then they report to the chief of staff.
So I can either ask the chief of staff a
question and then that Jarvis in my case
can go ask Victor, Mary or Bernie who
are specialists in editing, Agentic
Commerce, Deep Researcher. These are all
things I do for my writing. I do a ton
of research using AI. I write my papers.
I have an editor go through. I bounce
off suggestions with them. And then
Agenta Commerce is my favorite thing to
get news items on. So in this case
running the weekend tape scan now. So I
create these routines which show up over
here. They run these on their own. This
is not on my computer. This is in the
cloud. This is a massive moment. So when
I have my open claw and I have to use a
certain intelligence. I have to download
it onto my computer. I don't want it to
be around my files. This one is
integrated with my files and I love it.
It's also integrated with my login to my
apps. I'll show you some of that. Now,
I've expanded it. So, this is where I
wanted to go. And for you guys who
actually get it and try it. If you just
consistently put the sheets that I
upload to the subscriber website for my
technical pages for the fundamental
pages all to a folder and then you just
connect this to the folder one time and
just say, "Okay, I want you to connect
to this folder." And you give it the
location and you give it an instruction.
I only want you to use this for data.
You don't write anything. You don't save
anything. You don't do anything. You
just have it access it and then you can
go in and ask it questions like
how many of the names in technical sheet
were above the 50-day moving average the
last week and it goes through. Okay, how
many were above the two 20-day of the 72
that were above the 20? This takes it's
instant in terms of the reaction speed.
This is why you need to use it. Then you
can go even further and then you can
basically go now give me a list of how
many were above the 50-day moving
average by week by week. So, it gives me
that thing that I show you guys in terms
of how many are above from prior weeks.
It's taking it's going through all of
the files on the sheet and doing that.
If I want to go through which ones are
near the all-time highs or the furthest
away from all-time highs very quickly,
anything I want to get from it. And you
can see that I added agency, alpha,
signal, each one of these has a
different skill set that I'm using. You
can do this for anything. I connected
one and I called it call. This is my
earnings commentary one. So, all I got
to do in is put the stock symbol and
then it goes through and it gives me the
last four reported all of this stuff,
guys. And it takes seconds. It's just
how many ideas you can figure out and
where you can go. So, in this case, I
went into the computer. There's a
computer screen over here, which is on
the cloud. You sign into your site. It's
part of this. And then this one here,
alpha, I just go into it and say, "Give
me the bull bear case." And it goes to
X. I'm doing it on X. I want to see the
bull bear case and anything you can
connect to whatever apps you want inside
here. It's not on your computer. It's in
the cloud. Then you can go in and
create. Okay, I want to go through and I
want to make sure it's helping me get
ready for anything during the week. I
save my stuff into notion. It has a
notion notion plugin. So when it's
running stuff, it saves thing to its own
notion account uh notion uh folder. And
then I go look at it on Friday before I
do this with you guys to see if there's
anything else that I may have missed for
the week. So you can see how this goes.
It's got all these runs that it does for
me. I just wanted to make sure you guys
saw it. This thing is important. So to
finish up the week, Maderna shares more
than double on success of
MRNA cancer vaccine. I've talked about
this. I've said publicly we will start
being a in a place based on everything
that I read and talk to that by 2030 we
will be at the point where you can say
safely we will be able to stop all
disease in the foreseeable future that
people won't have to die from disease.
You have to think about what that means
for the stock market what that means for
companies what that means for the
deficit the debt all these things.
Again, you have to think forward on
these things, but we're getting now
things like a cancer vaccine. I wrote
this in November of last or in June of
this year on Eli Liy in terms of what's
going to happen, but I wrote this back
in November of 25 on how artificial
intelligence is transforming pharma's
broken economics. I highlighted some
things in there. I'm not going to read
it because I've gone further, but I did
ask JT GBT, "What would happen to the
stock market if humanity discovered a
true, widely accessible cure for
cancer." Its answer was blunt. Global
equities would likely surge 20 to 30%
almost immediately as markets replace
longer lifespans, longer health care
burden, lower healthcare burdens, and
higher future consumption.
Just think about what we're going
through. So the argument I made in that
November paper was that pharma was
entering a new place of a rerating.
Legacy pharma is a 5% growth thing with
25% free cash flow margin. It fails the
rule of 40 growth asset test. But if it
goes to 10 to 12 and free cash flow
improves because of the benefits that
come from AI both on the discovery side
and the efficacy side but also on the
efficiency side they would get it to a
rerating.
I believe multiples will go from 12 to
15 to 20 to 25. And this is one of the
reasons why I've said publicly
that Eli Liy will be the biggest company
in 5 years. So I believe Eli Liy is a
cash cow bringing in money on obesity
medicine that everyone would like to get
because it's the biggest problem in the
country. And if they get those, it has
huge implications for the revenues. And
as they're getting that cash in the
door, they are doing M&A like a drunken
sailor right now. They are buying up
companies because stage two IP is now
worth a lot of money if you believe by
taking it and you have your own AI data
center, which they do and you connected
to it, you should start to see more
value on this. And I can tell you from
the few people I know in the healthcare
side, they're not all over this. It's
science people that are, but there's too
many people that are doubting this. So,
you guys can read this on your own. It's
been an important week in my mind. We'll
see if Bitcoin can stay above the 200
day moving average. For those of you who
want to reach out, just call Mark, email
Mark Whailing. Um, I think it's an
important time. The crypto stuff will be
a video and papers that come out
probably weekly. They'll be on the
subscriber site, both the videos and
that. If you guys are interested, great.
You can go over to the website. This
will be part of everyone who's already
signed up as a subscriber. There's no
additional cost. It's just going on
there, which means if anyone subscribes
primarily for the crypto side, you're
going to get the AI side, too. You can
find out more about it. Have a great
week, guys. I will see you definitely
from Brooklyn next week. Sorry for the
little glitch in the video. Uh, but when
you're oneman show, sometimes you just
got to make do. See youa.